<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on Alper Yildirim</title><link>https://yildirimalper.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on Alper Yildirim</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yildirimalper.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Itertools or no itertools</title><link>https://yildirimalper.github.io/blog/itertools-or-no-itertools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yildirimalper.github.io/blog/itertools-or-no-itertools/</guid><description>Itertools, in a nutshell, is a beautiful python library that allows out-of-the-box computations and functions using lazy evaluation and iterators. What I like about them is that they could be adapted to work with large quantities of data in batch-processing and python ecosystem.
I learned about itertools in one of PyData talks and I was puzzled by what the speaker said at that time. He said:
&amp;ldquo;When I first saw itertools, I was thinking why anyone would ever need that?</description></item><item><title>How to calculate weighted average in PostgreSQL like a boss</title><link>https://yildirimalper.github.io/blog/how-to-calculate-weighted-average-in-postgresql-like-a-boss/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yildirimalper.github.io/blog/how-to-calculate-weighted-average-in-postgresql-like-a-boss/</guid><description>As the title says it all, this post is on how to perform weighted average in SQL, which is not a natively-supported aggregation function like sum() or avg(). In order to do so, we will exploit some math and window functions in a cunning 😈, yet logical way 🤓, than trying to pull out a physical solution.
In normal data engineering, this approach should not be preferred as it can be super hard to maintain, not scalable and confusing to other people but nevertheless this is a very useful, simple and intuitive hack I figured out myself for some quick data analysis and getting insights.</description></item></channel></rss>